Toho Co., Ltd.
November 1969 (Showa 44)
New Series Announcement
Finally starting with the New Year's issue
Be UP and surprised!
Nice...
Jumps out from the desk drawer!?
What will come out next month...
That time,
I, Fujiko F. Fujio
Are already out of ideas to create a new manga series, while the deadline is approaching
It makes me really depressed
Impossible!
If I can't still think of a new idea today, I will have no other time...
A figure that appears from the desk drawer...
a sentient being who lives in the drawer...
Suddenly appears
♪ Hello.. Hello.. I was shocked ♪
♪ If you want to play baseball, I can... ♪
How can this be?
Welcome home
There is not enough time, if only there is a time machine...
I will go to the future to steal my own idea...
If only...
right here, now...
There is a time machine...
Year 2112
The Birth of Doraemon
Just give up, Dormanstain!
Translator's Note: Dormanstain and the Man in Black/Black Mask
(Dinosaur Hunter) are the main villains in the 1980 movie: Nobita's Dinosaur and its 2006 remake
Don't call me a criminal if I surrender!
September 3, 2112
You can't run anymore!
We can be captured at this rate!
Everything is OK, TIME WARP!
Alas! They escaped again
Matsushiba Robot Factory
Are you okay?
This is the place for the incinerator
T..t..thank you! You saved me!
You're a robot cat too, huh?
Yes, my name is Doraemon
Translator's Note: Syokyakuro is a Japanese word for an incinerator
Noramiyako is my name, I'm a robot dancer
I've...
Just been born, so I'm still dazed
It looks like you fell from far above
We are both cat-shaped robot
Let's do our best together so that we can be useful to the community
Ro..roger!
See ya!
Oh no! I have to go too
All of you are robot cats that were created as civilian workers
to help people
At a special school, these robots learn diligently
For them to be robots that are automatic and possess a lot of skills
Okay?
Okay, Okay!
I will do my best!
Itadakimasu!
"Dokodemo Doa!"
Translation: Anywhere Door
Dokodemo Doa!
"Torinuke Hoop!"
Translation: Pass through Hoop
I don't know if your quality is not so good, or just a bad character?
I'm so sorry...
Created in the same factory with the same process as the others
But why are you the only one that is acting weird?
When you were created, did you lose a piece of screw?
Thump!
Or fell from a high place?
Thump! thump!
Robots that have poor quality
Will soon be thrown into the incinerator
I..i..incinerator?
Begin immediately!
I lied
Don't scare me like that...
I think there is a class that suits you better
Really? Classes are suitable for me?
Good, go there
Waaaah! The incinerator!
Sorry, wrong path
Don't joke me like that
Here... Here...
Today, a new student will be introduced
Tiger-shaped?
Oh, it's a cat-shaped
It looks stupid
Hey, don't fight
What's your name?
Ye..yes! I'm... Do..Doraemon
Everyone, please guide me
Doraemon!
Noramiyako!
I'm so happy, we're classmates
Who is he, he's so close with Noramiyako
He's just a new student, how dare him!
Hey, Doraemon!
Huh? What is it?
Translation: Fourth Dimensional Pocket
Give us your "Yojigen Pocket"!
Huh? Why?
A robot as stupid as you can't use advanced tools
Therefore, let us use it
No... no, I don't want to...
Leave that to us!
Give that! Quick!
Don't argue, give it to us!
No way! Stop!
Just give that to us!
What gadget is it?!
This.. is.. "Small Light"!
No batteries?!!
I told you that you're not able to use that properly!
You're just going to waste any good stuff
This one... that was...
Not this... this is not what I need...
Nyahahahaha!
Noramiyako!
Are you okay?
Thank you!
That is...?
A kemari ball
Translator's Note: Kemari is a form of football that was popular in Japan during the Heian Period
Taken from the Heian period
Heian period?
Translator's Note: Dorarinho is a member of The Doraemons. He is also a soccer pro.
Leave soccer to me!
All of you will stand outside!
♪ Itoshi no Nyao/Meow of Love♪/Yokoyama Chisa
♪ Itoshi no hitomi, Nyao    愛しの瞳　ニャーオ
Eyes of love, Meow!
Doraemon, tomorrow is graduation day where we can show our skills in school
♪ Daisuki da nyan, Meow   大好きだニャーン　ミャーオ
I love the sound of a cat makes, Meow!
Don't be so depressed like that
♪ Kawaikutte dokidoki shichau    かわいくってドキドキしちゃう
I was pretty nervous
But I'm... slow and stupid
I don't have any skill
♪ kimi ni muchuu   キミに夢中
Crazy about you
That's not true
Doraemon's true skill is that,
♪ Soba ni ikitai na, Nyao    そばにいきたいな　ニャーオ
I want to go near you, Meow!
he's always doing his best
So, cheer up, nee?
♪ Dakedo hazukashi, Meow   だけどはずかし　ミャーオ
But it's embarrasing, Meow!
You can give me a kiss if you want
Hooray!!
♪ Mitame yori mo Romanchisuto sa   見た目よりもロマンチストさ
It is more romantic than it looks
♪ Shinjite hoshii     信じてほしい
I want you to believe
I'm just kidding
Oh yes, this pocket...
♪ Chotto dake shai dakedo junjou sekaiichi    ちょっとだけシャイだけど　純情世界一
But I'm just a little bit shy, and also the most innocent in the world
can take objects from the past, this is a "Time Pocket"
Here, this is a snack from the 20th century, Dorayaki!
Translator's Note: Dorayaki consists of two small pancake-like patties  wrapped around a filling of sweet red bean paste.
Try to eat it to cheer you up
♪ Koi suru kimochi makenai yo    恋する気持ち　負けないよ
This feeling of love, I will not give up!
Itadakimasu!
Delicious!!
Doraemon, when you do something, you always mean it!
Robot Audition!
Graduates of the Robot School!
Soon, you will work actively for the community
Robot Audition!
This event is being broadcasted throughout the country via 3D TV
Dear TV viewers,
If you thought, "I want to have a robot like that"
Please immediately press the "OK" button in front of you
And the robot will be a volunteer directly for your family
Now, we will start the show!
Robot Audition!
It's started... already begun...
Don't be tense!
First of all is the Robot Gunman, Dora-the-Kid!
He has a quick shooting skill
This is dangerous!
The stage will be destroyed!
Congratulations!
You are selected by the Time Patrol as a member of special forces
The second student robot, a great tap-dancer, Doranichov!
If Doranichov sees moon shaped things, he will transform!
Unpredictable!
He is selected by the horror film club and an alien movie director!
♪I am Jaibee...♪
Jaibee... his skill is... singing...
It should be... but...
Doraemon! Use your tools and do something!
Yes! Yes!
"Uguisu-in no Omanjuu"
Translation: Mark of Uguisu Omanjuu!
(Uguisu is a bird - AKA Japanese Bush-warbler
Omanjuu - is a popular traditional Japanese confection)
Here!
♪I am Jaibee, a famous singer...♪
It's my turn now. What should I do? What should I do? I am nervous!
Use your tools and do something Doraemon!
Ehhhh?
"Kincho-Dori!"
Translation: Relaxing Bird
A robot that is good at talking, Sunekichi!
It seems that the relaxing effect is too strong!
Don't sleep on stage!
I'm so tired...
But both of you have been selected. I feel so relieved!
It's Noramiyako's turn!
The dancing robot, Noramiyako!
Awesome... awesome!
Next is your turn, right?
Oh no! I forgot!
Do your best!
Finally, the last robot
a baby-sitter robot, Doraemon!
I... I... am Doraemon
Ehhh... ummmm...
A baby rattle drum toy!
No, it's a mistake, this is a "Kaminari Yobidashi Daiko"
Translation: Lightning Summoning Drum
I can take a walk with your baby
Whoooah!! Waaaaah!
I'm fine, I'm fine...
The regulator speed is just set to maximum
Dear... dear...
Grandma, what's wrong with him?
We're sorry, the time is running out
Looks like there is no single vote...
Doraemon...
With this, the robot audition is now over
Finally!
It looks like he's directly selected by a baby
Doraemon, you've passed!
Hooray!
Ahahaha!
January 9, 2115
He just accidently pressed the button...
Umm... what about my future?
Doraemon...
Anyway, returning a robot is not good
Also, it seems that Sewashi likes you
Then, can I stay here?
Yes
Can you please help us in taking care of Sewashi?
Yes! I will do my best!
Sewashi, nice to meet you
Doraemon... Doraemon...
Wait for me! Wait for me!
Alright! If I use this 3D picture, I can certainly make a nice sculpture of Doraemon.
August 20, 2122
It seems that it has somewhat strange ears
Alright! Next, I will use a live mice editor to fix it
Can you fix Doraemon's ears a little?
Chuu! Doraemon's ears will be made like this
Ahh! You're wrong, you're wrong!
The sculpture is the one that should be repaired!
Do-Doraemon!!
Th...There is a mouse eating my ears!!!
Wow! Apparently because of a mice robot's mistake... right?
Translator's Note: The Robot Doctor's lines always end with "dakara ne". It is a Japanese grammar particle that solicits agreement.
Don't worry, he will be fine, right?
In a flash, all will be fixed! Right?
After all, ears are just for decoration, right?
But somehow, it must be repaired correctly, right?
Please help us
My apologies Doraemon, does it hurt?
I'll get well soon so don't worry.
We will be starting soon, right?
I'll just wait outside
Achoooooo!
Oh my! It's dangerous, right?!
Waaaaah!
Excuse me, I just want to see a patient here named Doraemon
Please go to the Sunflower Room
Oh, Sewashi
Doraemon, are you fine now? Huh?
Th-thank god he was already repaired
He seems to be more handsome than ever, right? Is it handsome brother?
Repair cost is free of charge, right? Aha-ha
Oh, I have something more to do!
Ahahahahahahaha
Your head... hahahahaha
There's no use in sulking! During times like this...
"Genki no Moto"!
Translation: Source of Energy
If I drink this, I will be in full spirit
I will be in....... full spirit...
Why did my sadness increase instead?
Why did I... become like this? Waaaaaah!
Hmmm... There! Brother!
Brother!
Brother?
Who are you?
My name is Dorami, I was created as an additional nanny robot.
I am your robot sister.
All of  a sudden I have a beautiful sister like you
Are you in good health?
Wha... what happened to you?
It is because of the cries of my deep sorrow...
My paint slowly began to peel
And my throat is so hoarse...
I don't want to live anymore!
But how come? Did you use a tool?
I drank "Genki no Moto"
Huh? Brother this is "Higeki no Moto"!
Translation: Source of Tragedy
Waaaah! No wonder I feel a great sadness!
Oh yes, Sewashi is looking for you, brother. He is missing!
Eh? Sewashi is missing?
It's all my fault!
Now is not the time to cry!
Oh yes, in times like this...
"Genki no moto"!
Brother! It is a "Denko Sekka" bottle!
Translation: Lightning Flash
Oh, right! What should I do? Wha.. what...
It's trouble! You can't stop moving once you drink it!
It's too late
I can't stop!
You can't run away again!
Damn Time Patrol!
Doraemon, where did you go?
Did you see that just now?
That little boy, huh?
We will take him as a hostage!
What a brilliant idea!
What are you doing?
If you still follow us, this kid will get hurt.
Damn!
Let me go! Let me go!
Doraemon!
Aaaaaaah!!!!
I can't stop myself, I can't stop!
Doraemon!
What happened?
The engine was clogged!
Where is this?
Why it is so hot here?
Waaah! We are in the incinerator!
It's finished.
Doraemon!
Sewashi!
I've changed into this yet you can still recognize me?
Of course!
It looks like you're more handsome than before.
Thank you Sewashi!
♪ Hello! Dorami-chan!♪/Yamano Satoko
Everyone is worried about you.
♪ Dorami Dorami Dorami Dora   ドラミ　ドラミ　ドラミドラ
That's right, let's go home immediately
♪ Rarara Rarara MimiDorami!  ラララ　ラララ　ミミドラミ
It seems that I dropped my pocket!
♪ Ramido! Ramido! RamiDorami!   ラミド　ラミド　ラミドラミ
Doraemon!
Sewashi, we came to fetch you!
♪ Haroo! Daisuki Dorami-chan  ハロー！ だいすきドラミちゃん
Hello! I love you! Dorami-chan!
Dorami!
Noramiyako!
♪ Jikan o hora ne taimu mashin de   じかんをほらね　タイムマシンで
In our time machine, flying through time!
Doraemon forgive me, I was laughing so hard and may jaw is now aching
♪ Atchi e kotchi e tonde yuku   あっちへ　こっちへ　とんでゆく
Over here! Over there! Flying on and on!
Finally, I'm able to understand your feelings
♪ Mirai no kuni no suupaa robotto   みらいのくにの　スーパーロボット
A super robot from a future land!
Seeing your head and body color, it looks like you're so handsome
♪ Makka na ribon no Dorami-chan   まっかなリボンの　ドラミちゃん
Deep red ribbon! Dorami-chan!
Really?
Huh? Your voice is so sexy? I think I'm liking you more and more!
♪ Sooraa yotto poketto Paa! Paa! Paa!  ソーラーヨット　ポケット　パッ！パッ！パッ！
Solar Yacht! Pocket! Pa pa pa!
♪ Minna no yume he to tsuretette  みんなのゆめへと　つれてって
Take us all along to dreamland!
I'm happy!
Here you go, Doraemon!
I made it myself
Wow! Thank you, Sewashi!
But... I don't have any gift for you...
Stupid! I don't need any gifts!
Just as long as Doraemon is my friend, it will be the most precious gift for me
Yes, we will be friends forever!
Doraemon!
Sewashi!
The cake is ready!
We're already waiting!
It's great!
In addition, there is also a lot of dorayaki
Ouch!
Do-ra-ra!
Principal Teraodai!
Doraemon, you're very terrific!
You've helped the Time Patrol
In order to commemorate that,
We've created a robot that looks just like you, the Mini-dora
Eh? Mini-dora?
In addition to that,
Here is a Christmas gift for you
A new fourth dimensional pocket!
Wow! Thank you so much, sir!
If so, use now a gadget for celebration from the pocket
Okay!
"Kanpai no Tane!"
Translation: Cheers' Seeds (direct translation) or Seed of Celebration
Is this sake?
It is juice, not sake!
Then I'm allowed to drink this
Come on everyone, let's toast!
Merry Christmas!
April 5, 2123
After that,
I was sent back to the past by Sewashi
...in order to fix the life of his grandfather
Nobi Nobita
In order to make him happy,
I was sent to him as a Christmas gift
What is it?
A dream, huh?
In the end, I still haven't made anything
I'm so pathetic...
Eureka!
A manga about a robot from the future who helps a manga auth...
It's not that... but instead helping a careless boy
It seems to be so interesting
A robot
In his bag, there are many powerful gadgets of the future
Well, his name is...
Doraemon!
Translator's Note: "Dora" is from "dora neko" (brazen or stray cat), and is a corruption of nora (stray). "-emon" is a component of male given names.
I am Doraemon!
"Boku Doraemon 2112 | I am Doraemon 2112"
♪Nobuyo Oyama and Koorogi '73
Atama tekateka Saete pikapika
My mind is great! Great! Swift and shiny! Shiny!
Original Author: Fujiko F. Fujio
Director: Zen Souichirou
Voice Actors
Doraemon: Nobuyo Oyama
Yellow Doraemon: Chisa Yokoyama
Sewashi: Oota Yoshiko
Dorami: Keiko Yokozawa
Noramiyako: Yuuko Minaguchi
Principal Teraodai: Nagai Ichiro
Fujiko F. Fujio: Yada Minoru
Sore ga doushita Boku Doraemon
But, what does it matter, I am Doraemon
Voice Actors
Wang Dora: Nishihara Kumiko
El Matadora: Ikura Kazu
Dorarinho: Suzuki Mie
Jaibee: Tatekabe Kazuya
Sunekichi: Kimotsuki Kaneta
Strict Robot Teacher: Tanaka Ryouichi
Dormanstain: Chikao Ohtsuka
Man in Black: Hirose Masashi
Robot Doctor: Matsuo Ginsan
Mirai no sekai no neko ga robotto
Created in the future world, Cat-type Robot
Subtitles based on the script of
turtlepod.org
(http://www.doraemon.mangawiki.org)
Donna mondai boku Doraemon
How about that! I am Doraemon
Song Translations based on the releases of
RocketGang Subs (Hello! Dorami-chan)
Nya!Fansubs (Boku Doraemon 2112)
Kimyou kiteretsu makafushigi
Mysterious, enigmatic, mystifying
Revision and Additional Subtitles
Typesetter
dorakki2112
Kisou tengai shisha gonyuu
Bizaare, and rounded
Timer/Encoder
thedoraemons
Demae jinsoku rakugaki muyou
Clockwork-run and no need for instruction
DVD RAW Provider
riskman
Doraemon Doraemon
Quality Check
dorakki2112
zefiru
Honwaka Pappa Honwaka Pappa
Doraemon
Doraemon Doraemon
Honwaka Pappa Honwaka Pappa
Doraemon
"2112-nen Doraemon no Tanjou"
Production Commitee
Fujiko Pro
Shogakukan
TV Asahi Broadcasting
ADK
Shinei Animation
© 1995
THE END!
Presented by
Contact ➋➁nd Century Subs